catchannel.com 2012-11-24

# CatChannel.com

|  | 

---  
  
Animal Network Privacy Policy 

**Effective January 1, 2005**

BowTie, Inc., formerly Fancy Publications, Inc., is committed to bringing you information that is tailored to your individual needs and, at the same time, to protecting your privacy.  The following is a summary of the various ways we gather and disseminate the information you provide when purchasing our products and services and when using our websites.  We use the information we collect to provide you with the products you have purchased or the services you have registered for and also to enhance your overall Internet experience.  This policy also provides information on how you can opt out of certain disclosures of information we may collect. 

This policy describes how BowTie, Inc., and its corporate affiliates Kennel Club Books, LLC, Global Distribution Services, LLC and Thoroughbred Times Company Inc. (collectively, BowTie), collect, use and disclose information online and offline from subscribers and from users of the [www.bowtieinc.com](http://www.bowtieinc.com/) website, and other BowTie-operated websites, such as the Animal Network website at [www.animalnetwork.com](http://www.animalnetwork.com/), and the websites that correspond to various BowTie publications.  Links to the various BowTie publications appear on the Animal Network website.  The BowTie-operated websites are referred to collectively as the BowTie Websites.

**SCOPE  
** This privacy policy covers only BowTies online and offline collection and treatment of information.  BowTie does not control the privacy policies of advertisers or non-affiliated websites that may be linked to the BowTie Websites.  We are not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of non-BowTie Websites.  If you click on any ads or non-affiliated links, we encourage you to read the privacy statements of these other websites and entities, which may be different from our privacy policy. ****

****TYPES OF INFORMATION COLLECTED  
**** Several different types of information may be collected from subscribers and users of the BowTie Websites, including the following:

****Personally Identifiable Information** : ** This type of information is any information that can be used to identify, contact or locate a BowTie subscriber or user of the BowTie Websites individually.  Examples include your name, address, email address, telephone number and credit card number. Credit card information is used solely for processing your orders from BowTie. When you register or use a service or make a purchase, BowTie collects personally identifiable information from you.  We do not automatically collect any personally identifiable information. BowTie only collects personally identifiable information when you affirmatively provide it to us.  For instance, when you register for our services, enter a sweepstakes or contest, complete a survey or subscribe to our magazines, you are asked to provide information such as your email address, mailing address, name, or phone number. Optional information such as your age or gender may also be requested.  Unless you expressly inform us that you do not want your personally identifiable information shared, we may share such information with third parties.

****Non-Personal or Aggregate Information** :** This type of information does not identify a subscriber or website user individually, but instead includes general information such as age range, occupation and gender, or how the BowTie Websites are used, such as visits to a particular page.  Non-personal information may be collected from you automatically when you use the BowTie Websites or voluntarily if you provide it to us.  This information does not consist of personally identifiable information.  Instead, the information collected automatically may include non-personal information such as browser type, geographic location, IP address, advertisements viewed or selected, searches conducted on the BowTie, and subscription or other preferences. This information may be lumped together and shared with third parties. For example, we may inform our advertisers that a certain percentage of our subscribers or website users fall within a certain age range or are from a certain geographic area, without disclosing the personally identifiable information of any one individual.

****HOW WE COLLECT INFORMATION  
**** When you subscribe to our publications or register for our services, such as our online discussion forums, we collect personally identifiable information, which may include your name, physical address, email address, phone numbers, and billing information. We may also collect personally identifiable information through purchase forms, surveys, contests and sweepstakes entries, emails we receive from you, and other interactions with the BowTie Websites in which you voluntarily provide such information.  
  
When you use the BowTie Websites we may collect a variety of technical data, including but not limited to your IP address, domain, and web browser information. We may also track the page you visited before coming to the BowTie Websites, and the page you link to when you leave the BowTie Websites, which of our pages you access, and the ads that you view.    
  
The BowTie Websites use cookies, which are small pieces of non-personal information stored on your computer. The use of cookies allows the BowTie Websites to recognize previous visitors, record page views, and recall certain information a visitor entered previously.  For instance, a cookie may store your password, or note that you're interested in ferrets. You can choose to decline cookies by setting your browser to reject them, but if you do, some parts of the BowTie Websites may not operate properly.  We may also use tracking images, applets and web beacons to collect the same information.  
  
We may use third-party advertising companies to serve or display ads on the BowTie Websites. These companies may employ cookies and web beacons to measure advertising effectiveness.  Any information that these third parties collect via cookies and action tags is anonymous.  
  
Finally, we may also allow third parties to collect aggregate and other anonymous information about our visitors through the BowTie Websites.   Should we begin allowing third parties to collect personally identifiable information about visitors to the BowTie Websites, we will inform visitors of these activities at the location of the collection.

****HOW WE USE COLLECTED INFORMATION  
**** BowTie uses this information to provide you with the products or services you have requested.  For example, if you subscribe to one of our magazines, we may use your email address to send you a confirmation notice and your address to send you your magazine.  Similarly, if you enter contests, we will use this information to notify you if you are a winner. This information may also be used to target advertising or customize website presentation and layout. This information may also be used to store your account information, website session information (such as products in your shopping cart), order status and purchase history. We may also use this information to send you newsletters, inform you about new features, products or services, or other changes to the services or our policies. We may share this information with other BowTie corporate affiliates. In addition, unless you expressly opt out, BowTie may also make its subscriber lists or personally identifiable information, such as contact information, available to companies that offer products and services that we believe may interest our subscribers or website users.  If you do not want us to share your personally identifiable information, you may inform us of your choice to opt out by following the procedure in the Your Options section immediately below.  ****

We may also share or disclose personally identifiable information about you to third parties when (1) we use such third parties to provide products or services on our behalf, such as to fulfill subscriptions; (2) you enter a contest or sweepstakes, in which case we may give your personal information to the sponsor who may use it for marketing purposes; (3) as required by law; (4) as necessary to protect our legal rights; and (5) in connection with any sale, merger, transfer or other disposition of all or a portion of the business.

Although personally identifiable information is protected as outlined above, we reserve the right to use and share aggregated anonymous data about our subscribers and users.

**YOUR OPTIONS FOR CONTROLLING PERSONALLY IDENTIFIABLE INFORMATION  
** If you do not want us to share your personally identifiable information for marketing purposes, you may inform us of your choice to opt out by e-mailing [privacy@bowtieinc.com](mailto:privacy@bowtieinc.com) to let us know. In your email, you must provide us with sufficient information to identify you **(name, address, email address that was provided to us, or as it appears on your subscriber label or promotion, and the magazine name)** so that we can ensure we can identify you and complete your request. Opting out of personal information sharing for marketing purposes may not prohibit sharing for non-marketing purposes, such as for completing requested transactions.

**CALIFORNIA RESIDENTS  
** California Civil Code Section 1798.83 permits California residents to request certain information regarding disclosures of personal information that has been collected online or offline to third parties for direct marketing purposes.  If you would like to request an information disclosure, e-mail [californiaprivacy@bowtieinc.com](mailto:californiaprivacy@bowtieinc.com) **.**

**WHAT ELSE YOU SHOULD KNOW ABOUT PRIVACY**

******Reviewing and Correcting Information  
** You can currently edit your discussion forum profile, including your identifier and contact information at any time, by clicking on Your Profile on any of the BowTie Websites.  If you forget your forum password, you can e-mail us at [forums@bowtieinc.com.](mailto:forums@bowtieinc.com.)  After verifying your identity, we will e-mail you your password.

You can also edit and update your subscription account information at any time by visiting our online Subscription Services section on any of the BowTie Websites.

**Security  
** Although BowTie uses industry-standard encryption technologies to protect certain data transferred to and received to and from the BowTie Websites and although BowTie maintains security measures in place in order to protect against the loss, misuse or alteration of personally identifiable information under our control, the Internet and other networking communication media cannot be guaranteed to be 100% secure.  Accordingly, you transmit information at your own risk and BowTie assumes no responsibility or liability for disclosure of your information due to errors in transmission, unauthorized or illegal access or other causes beyond BowTies reasonable control. 

**Disclosure of Information in Public Areas  
** Personally identifiable information that you disclose in a public area of the BowTie Websites, such as our discussion forums, may be collected and used by others who may then send you messages or other communications that you do not want to receive.  BowTie does not control the actions of the users of our discussion forums.  Accordingly, you should exercise discretion in the type of information you decide to post in our discussion forums.  If you do decide to disclose personally identifiable information in a forum, you do so at your own risk.

**PRIVACY CONCERNS AND CHILDREN  
** The BowTie Websites, including all public discussion forums, are intended for those who are at least 13 years old.  We do not knowingly accept personally identifiable information from anyone under 13.  Children under 13 are not permitted to use our public discussion forums or otherwise provide us with any personally identifiable information, as detailed in our [Terms of Use](pub:/animalnetwork/corporate/terms.aspx). Likewise, those under the age of 18 are prohibited from making purchases, including subscriptions, on the BowTie Websites. Children under 18 should only use the BowTie Websites under the supervision of their parents or guardians.  Parents:  if your children disclose information about themselves in our public discussion forums, they may get unsolicited messages from other parties.  Accordingly, you should discourage them from disclosing personally identifiable information in such discussion forums.

**CHANGES TO OUR PRIVACY POLICY  
** We may make revisions to our privacy policy from time to time.  If you are concerned how information is collected and used by BowTie, we encourage you to review our website periodically to read the latest version. 

**CONTACT INFORMATION  
** Questions and suggestions regarding our privacy policy should be sent by e-mail to [privacy@bowtieinc.com](mailto:privacy@bowtieinc.com).  You can also reach us by mail at P.O. Box 6040, Mission Viejo, 92690. Please address your correspondence to Privacy Policy.

 Give us your opinion on  
Animal Network Privacy Policy

| 

very good!

**Marla, Atlanta, GA  
Posted: 3/26/2009 10:20:30 PM**  
  
---  
  
In the contest (under your tab for contests) for most colorful there's an entry of a Maine coon called Bob Cat.  
It was entered in the contest late last night. He had 51 votes almost immediately.  
When the siamese call Ollie started to get close to the 51 votes Bob Cat had the total went almost immediately again (within 1 hour) to 101. I think the owner is Stacking the vote. (possibly by using fakes email addresses)  
Please investigate it's not fair.  
Thank you,  
Kenneth Buck

**Kenneth Buck, Clearwater, FL  
Posted: 9/9/2006 6:02:25 PM**
